How did I do this? I can’t explain it.
How do billions of tiny birds cross the world’s largest desert, every year, without food or water?
When humans look at our route on a map, they realise that that no sane creature would cross it.
It is insane, when you think about it.
So we do not think. There is no space in our bodies for thoughts.
All the energy goes to the flight. Because our bodies know that, no matter how dangerous that journey is, what we leave behind is worse.
And we want to live. So we fly.
I flew non-stop for fifty hours. Two full days and two full nights.
The night air was freezing cold, the daytime sun scorching hot.
There were thousands, millions of us in the air, all moving in the same direction, racing on the most dangerous highway.
Yet, during the crossing, we were alone.
I crossed like I was in a dream, the adrenaline pumping through my veins, making my wings move as if they were not my own, giving me a strength I didn’t know I had.
I couldn’t feel the pain, the hunger, the cold, the exhaustion.
“You’re almost there”, my ancestors whispered.
My mom told me it was like hatching eggs. You don’t know how you do it, nature shows you how.
You just do it, and then you forget. Nobody wants to remember the pain, otherwise you wouldn’t have the strength to do it again.
And then, I made it to the other side.
There may have been an oasis. Or a city. I don’t remember any of it.
I simply remember that I landed somewhere and I passed out.
But in my dreams, I knew I was safe.